Grimy coffee cups, dirty clothes all over the floor and uninvited guests – and they're not even yours!
沾满污垢的咖啡杯、散落一地的脏衣服、不请自来的访客——这些东西甚至都不是你的！
These are the joys of flatsharing.
这就是合租的“乐趣”所在。
So why do we do it?
那么我们为什么还要选择合租呢？
Well, for many, buying a house or flat is just too expensive.
对很多人来说，买房或买公寓实在太贵了。
In fact, according to the Guardian, the total amount of rent paid by tenants in Britain in 2017 rose to more than £50 billion – more than double the level of ten years prior.
事实上，据《卫报》报道，2017年英国租客支付的房租总额高达500多亿英镑，是十年前的两倍多。
And for those who do, many choose to share the place with strangers to save money.
就算是租房，很多人也会选择和陌生人合租来省钱。
You rent a room and share the kitchen, living room and bathroom, for example.
比如你租下一间卧室，和别人共用厨房、客厅和浴室。
But apart from the financial saving, what are the pros and cons of flatsharing?
但除了省钱，合租还有哪些利弊呢？
The pros?
好处有哪些呢？
Well, living with others means that you can pool your resources.
和别人一起住意味着你们可以共享资源。
You may not even need to ask; just leave an IOU.
你甚至都不用开口求助，留下一张欠条就行。
Then there's the fact that you gain access to their social networks.
此外，你还能接触到室友的社交圈。
Living with people means meeting their friends, who may then become your friends.
和别人同住就意味着会认识他们的朋友，而这些人说不定也会成为你的朋友。
And don't forget the networking opportunity.
还有一点不容忽视，那就是拓展人脉的机会。
Lastly, there's the emotional support.
最后，合租还能带来情感上的支持。
Due to the nature of communal living, you're not just dealing with your own life events, but other people's too.
基于集体生活的属性，你要面对的不只是自己的生活琐事，也会参与到别人的生活中。
Most likely, there'll always be a shoulder to cry on when you need one.
当你需要倾诉时，很可能总会有人愿意借你一个肩膀哭泣。
But don't forget to reciprocate when they need it.
但别忘了，当他们需要帮助时，你也要投桃报李。
Now the cons.
再来说说弊端。
There's limited storage space, for a start.
首先，储物空间会很有限。
In most cases, the kitchen, for example, will be divvied up into designated shelves and areas.
比如大多数情况下，厨房里的架子和区域都会被划分好，分配给每个人专用。
Worse, many people may not respect these boundaries.
更糟的是，很多人可能不会遵守这些界限。
You might well come home to find someone's pilfered your milk or shower gel, and no one owns up to it.
你很可能下班回家后发现，自己的牛奶或沐浴露被人偷偷享用了，却没人承认。
Furthermore, despite the rota showing that cleaning is everyone's responsibility, some people don't like to pull their weight.
此外，即便清洁排班表上写着打扫卫生是每个人的责任，有些人就是不愿尽责出力。
And then there are the unexpected guests.
还有那些不请自来的访客也很让人头疼。
If a flatmate forgets to keep you in the loop about a party they're throwing and all you want is a quiet night, it can be challenging.
如果室友要办派对却忘了告诉你，而你只想安安静静地度过一晚，那场面就会很尴尬。
Whether the pros outweigh the cons is something everyone must decide for themselves.
合租到底是利大于弊还是弊大于利，每个人都得自己做决定。
Some people prefer their own space, while others thrive in a social environment.
有些人更喜欢独处的空间，而有些人则在社交环境中如鱼得水。
Regardless, for many who lack the means to buy their own property, a flatshare is, and will continue to be, a necessity.
但无论如何，对于许多没有能力购置房产的人来说，合租现在是、未来也依然会是一种刚需。